(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
デジタルメッセージボード
Digital Message Board
hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade
hololive stage DAY2
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
グッズ ラインナップ 紹介
オンライン通販も開始！
Goods Lineup Introduction
Online sales have also started!
ホロスターズ
HOLOSTARS
ホロライブ 事務所グッズ
hololive Office Goods
HOLOLIVE ALTERNATIVE グッズ
HOLOLIVE ALTERNATIVE Goods
マンカート ビームス コラボグッズ
MANGART BEAMS Collaboration Goods
holo*27 コラボグッズ
holo*27 Collaboration Goods
商品ラインナップ！
Product Lineup!
holo*27 コラボグッズ
holo*27 Collaboration Goods
BUSHIROAD グッズ
BUSHIROAD Goods
GOOD SMILE COMPANY グッズ
GOOD SMILE COMPANY Goods
OFFICIAL ITEMS
PENLIGHT COLORS
デジタルメッセージボード
Digital Message Board
グッズラインナップ紹介
Goods Lineup Introduction
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiss Schwarz!
ホロライブプロダクションが、またまたカードに大集合！
Hololive Production gathers once again on cards!
ひろがるヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Expanding Weiss Schwarz!
ブースターパック ホロライブプロダクション Vol.2、3月24日(金)発売！
Booster Pack Hololive Production Vol.2, on sale Friday, March 24th!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade × JOYSOUND スペシャルコラボレーション
hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade × JOYSOUND Special Collaboration
Our Bright Parade x JOYSOUND スペシャルコラボレーション
Our Bright Parade x JOYSOUND Special Collaboration
第1弾 2023.3.15-4.20 / 第2弾 2023.4.21-5.28
Vol. 1: 2023.3.15-4.20 / Vol. 2: 2023.4.21-5.28
コラボドリンクをご注文の方に、オリジナルコースタープレゼント！
Original coasters will be given to those who order collaboration drinks!
過去ライブの配信や豪華賞品が当たるキャンペーンなど他にも企画が盛りだくさん！
There are many other projects such as distribution of past lives and campaigns to win luxurious prizes!
ハクチライム 全てバイバイバイ まるみに出た ビビッとおかえり
Hakuchirime, all bye-bye-bye, rounded out, welcome back with a spark
だって全開 やっちゃって もうやめて したい
Because it's at full throttle, just do it, stop it already, I want to
どうしちゃったの 絶対好きでしょ
What's wrong? You must love it
Are you embarrassed? Right now, we're pushing some hot buttons.
hololive SUPER EXPO 2023 グッズラインナップ紹介
hololive SUPER EXPO 2023 Goods Lineup Introduction
商品ラインナップ！
Product lineup!
ホロスターズ グッズラインナップ紹介
HOLOSTARS Goods Lineup Introduction
hololive production Art Collection, サコッシュ, ピンバッジ, B2タペストリー
hololive production Art Collection, Sacoche, Pin badge, B2 tapestry
ホロライブ事務所グッズ
hololive Office Goods
HOLOLIVE ALTERNATIVE グッズ
HOLOLIVE ALTERNATIVE Goods
マンガート ビームス コラボグッズ
MANGART BEAMS Collaboration Goods
holo*27 コラボグッズ
holo*27 Collaboration Goods
BUSHIROAD グッズ
BUSHIROAD Goods
GOOD SMILE COMPANY グッズ
GOOD SMILE COMPANY Goods
OFFICIAL ITEMS
Our Bright Parade PENLIGHT COLORS
デジタルメッセージボード
Digital Message Board
ホロライブ SUPER EXPO 2023 デジタルメッセージボード
hololive SUPER EXPO 2023 Digital Message Board
デジタルメッセージボード
Digital Message Board
hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade
グッズラインナップ紹介
Goods Lineup Introduction
商品ラインナップ！
Product Lineup!
ホロスターズ グッズ
HOLOSTARS Goods
商品ラインナップ！
Product Lineup!
ホロライブ事務所グッズ
hololive Office Goods
HOLOLIVE ALTERNATIVE グッズ
HOLOLIVE ALTERNATIVE Goods
マンガート ビームス コラボグッズ
MANGART BEAMS Collaboration Goods
holo*27 コラボグッズ
holo*27 Collaboration Goods
BUSHIROAD グッズ
BUSHIROAD Goods
GOOD SMILE COMPANY グッズ
GOOD SMILE COMPANY Goods
OFFICIAL ITEMS
Our Bright Parade PENLIGHT COLORS
PENLIGHT COLORS
デジタルメッセージボード
Digital Message Board
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiß Schwarz!
ホロライブプロダクションが...
Hololive Production is once again...
...またまたカードに大集合！
...gathering on cards!
ひろがるヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Expanding Weiß Schwarz!
ブースターパック ホロライブプロダクション Vol.2、
Booster Pack Hololive Production Vol.2,
3月24日(金)発売！
on sale March 24th (Fri)!
ブシロード
Bushiroad
Our Bright Parade x JOYSOUND スペシャルコラボレーション
Our Bright Parade x JOYSOUND Special Collaboration
hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade x JOYSOUND スペシャルコラボレーション
hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade x JOYSOUND Special Collaboration
悪辣も持てば倍だ倍 マルギヌス・タピオアケ
If you have malice, it'll double and double. Marginus Tapioake...
だって全開やんなっちゃってもうやめていたい
Because I'm completely fed up and want to stop.
どうしちゃったの 絶対絶対大好きでしょ
What's wrong? You definitely, definitely love it, right?
Are you embarrassed? Or now you're blushing some?
hololive SUPER EXPO 2023 グッズラインナップ紹介
hololive SUPER EXPO 2023 Merchandise Lineup Introduction
PENLIGHT COLORS
hololive SUPER EXPO 2023 Our Bright Parade デジタルメッセージボード
hololive SUPER EXPO 2023 Our Bright Parade Digital Message Board
デジタルメッセージボード
Digital Message Board
#ひろがるホロライブDAY2
#SpreadHololiveDAY2
グッズラインナップ紹介
Goods Lineup Introduction
商品ラインナップ！
Product Lineup!
ホロスターズ 商品ラインナップ！
HOLOSTARS Product Lineup!
商品ラインナップ！
Product Lineup!
ホロライブ事務所グッズ 商品ラインナップ！
Hololive Office Goods Product Lineup!
商品ラインナップ！
Product Lineup!
マンガート ビームス コラボグッズ 商品ラインナップ！
Mangart Beams Collaboration Goods Product Lineup!
holo*27 コラボグッズ 商品ラインナップ！
holo*27 Collaboration Goods Product Lineup!
BUSHIROAD グッズ 商品ラインナップ！
BUSHIROAD Goods Product Lineup!
GOOD SMILE COMPANY グッズ 商品ラインナップ！
GOOD SMILE COMPANY Goods Product Lineup!
OFFICIAL ITEMS 商品ラインナップ！
OFFICIAL ITEMS Product Lineup!
PENLIGHT COLORS
デジタルメッセージボード
Digital Message Board
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiß Schwarz!
ホロライブプロダクションが、またまたカードに大集合！
Hololive Production members are gathering on cards once again!
ひろがるヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Expanding Weiß Schwarz!
ブースターパック ホロライブプロダクション Vol.2 3月24日発売！
Booster Pack: Hololive Production Vol.2, on sale March 24th!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
スペシャルコラボレーション
Special Collaboration
コラボドリンクをご注文の方に、オリジナルコースタープレゼント！
Original coaster gift for those who order a collab drink!
holo*27 NOW ON SALE!
Are you embarrassed? Is your face flushing somehow?
Natsuiro Matsuri Birthday Live :START
トワ様しか勝たん
Towa-sama is the best!
乾杯! Cheers!
Cheers! Cheers!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
夏色まつり
Natsuiro Matsuri
湊あくあ
Minato Aqua
紫咲シオン
Murasaki Shion
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
戌神ころね
Inugami Korone
兎田ぺこら
Usada Pekora
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
常闇トワ
Tokoyami Towa
雪花ラミィ
Yukihana Lamy
桃鈴ねね
Momosuzu Nene
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
ムーナ・ホシノヴァ
Moona Hoshinova
アーニャ・メルフィッサ
Anya Melfissa
パヴォリア・レイネ
Pavolia Reine
森カリオペ
Mori Calliope
がうる・ぐら
Gawr Gura
IRyS
セレス・ファウナ
Ceres Fauna
オーロ・クロニー
Ouro Kronii
ハコス・ベールズ
Hakos Baelz
hololive 4th fes.
Our Bright Parade
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
それぞれ違った心で
With hearts that are each different
走り出そう
Let's start running
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に
No matter where I looked, in a pitch-black place
芽生えてた
It was beginning to sprout
ほんの小さなきらめきに
In just a tiny sparkle
この瞳奪われた
My eyes were captivated
不安で揺れる心を
My heart that wavers with anxiety
うまくチューニングして
Tuning it just right
ほんの小さな
Just a tiny...
勇気を
Give me the courage
振り絞って言いたいよ
I want to muster up and say it
諦めの文字
The word "giving up"
デリートして進む
I'll delete it and move forward
苦しい時も
Even when it's hard
もう私は
I'm already
一人じゃないから
no longer alone
だからもっと 夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams more
ワクワク止まらない
I can't stop the excitement
想像を超えてゆく
Going beyond imagination
世界に見せてあげる
I'll show it to the world
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try accessing it
後悔なんてさせない
I won't let you regret it
それぞれ違った
Each and every different
心で
heart
走れGO!
Run, GO!
七色の空に輝く まぶしい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the seven-colored sky
見たことのない光を
A light I've never seen before
リアルに届けるよ
I'll deliver it to reality
いつも聞こえてくる歌に キャプチャして
Capture the songs I always hear
また新しい光を
Looking for a new light again
探したくなるよ
I feel like I want to
君の笑顔は
Your smile is
合成して進む
combining and moving forward
悲しい時に 見返すよ
I'll look back at it when I'm sad
ちからが湧くから
Because strength wells up
胸を張って 夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams with my head held high
奇跡のストーリー
A story of miracles
一緒に作ろう
Let's create it together
終わらない夢を
A never-ending dream
誰一人欠かせない
Not a single person can be missing
愛が待つこの世界
In this world where love waits
それぞれ違った
Each and every different
心で
heart
彩れ!
Color it!
悲しい時も
Even when it's sad
寂しい時も
Even when it's lonely
信じ合えるものがある
There are things we can believe in together
忘れずに この鼓動を
Without forgetting, this heartbeat
鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep making it sound
終わらない世界に
To the never-ending world
溢れ出すよ
It overflows
笑顔たち
The smiles
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way
時には涙して
Sometimes shedding tears
また笑い合いたい
I want to laugh together again
同じ未来も見たい
I want to see the same future too
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そう
Let's step forward
奇跡の 一歩を
The first step of miracles
意地っ張って 夢追いかけたい
Chasing my dream, being stubborn
ワクワク止まらない
I can't stop the excitement
想像を超えてゆく
Going beyond imagination
世界に見せてあげる
I'll show it to the world
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try accessing it
後悔なんてここにない
Regret doesn't exist here
それぞれ違った
Each and every different
心で
heart
作るわ!
I'll create it!
ハーイ、皆様お待たせいたしました！
Hi, everyone! Sorry to keep you waiting!
ここからは、スーパー白上タイム、
From here on, it's Super Shirakami Time,
略してSSTのお時間じゃーい！
SST for short! It's time!
イエーイ！
Yay!
盛り上がっていきましょー！
Let's get excited!
コンコンきつね！白上フブキです！
Kon kon kitsune! I'm Shirakami Fubuki!
オタ活とお茶とゲームが大好きオタクのバーチャル狐です！
I'm a virtual fox geek who loves fan activities, tea, and games!
色んなことして毎日楽しく活動してるのです！
I do all sorts of things and enjoy my activities every day!
フブちゃん、フブキ、白上、皆様お好きに呼んでください！
Fubu-chan, Fubuki, Shirakami, please call me whatever you like!
動画はじめての人も
For those seeing my videos for the first time,
いつも見てくれてる人も
And for those who always watch them,
一人一人のちからで
With the power of each and every one of you,
私はココにいます！
I am here!
ずっと変わらないこの場所で
In this place that will never change,
意味だって意思だってFakeじゃない
Neither meaning nor will is a fake
まだまだ道の途中
I'm still on my way
慌ただしく過ぎる日々は
The days that pass by busily
宝物ですよ
are treasures
泣いたって欲張ったって大丈夫
It's okay to cry or be greedy
笑顔で一緒にハイ！ハイ！
Let's smile together, hi! hi!
心を歌に重ねて
Let our hearts overlap in the song
届け！
Reach out!
Hirogarimashou my happy day
Let's spread my happy day
はじまるよ　今日は何をして遊びましょうか？
It's starting! What shall we do for fun today?
お茶でも飲んでひと息いってライブ二日目！
Let's have some tea, take a breath, and enjoy the second day of the live!
皆さんのこと　もっと知れたら私も幸せなのです
Knowing more about all of you makes me happy too
突っ張ったり　アピールしたり　皆さんせーのでご一緒に！
Let's push forward and appeal together on the count of three!
楽しくて　飛び跳ねる時も
In moments of joy when we're jumping around
悲しくて　落ち込む時も
And in moments of sadness when we're feeling down
皆さんのそばでちょっと
Right by your side...
私がそこにいます
...I will always be there
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai!
さあ　今もずっと変わらない思いだから
Now, because these feelings will never change
君と誰だって　どこだって welcome
With you, anyone and anywhere is welcome
ワクワク成長中
Excitement is growing
同じ時を過ごす今が
This moment we spend together
幸せなんですよ
Is true happiness
泣いたって　しょげたって　大丈夫ジョーブ
Even if you cry or feel blue, it's okay, okay
笑顔で一緒に　ハイ・ファイ・ファイ！
With a smile, let's do a high-five! Five! Five!
輝く色重ねて
Layering the shining colors
広げましょう my the new world
Let's spread "my the new world"
大空も飛び越えて
Flying beyond the great sky
世界を回ったら
As we travel around the world
いつの果てまでも
Until the end of time
心通わせよう
Let our hearts connect
どこだって届けるよ
I'll reach you anywhere
いつだって知ってるよ
I always know
誰だって繋がるよ
Everyone can connect
ここから始めよう
Let's start from here
さあ皆さん　サイリウムを上に！
Now everyone, raise your penlights!
今日は幕張　みんなでせーの！
Today is Makuhari! Everyone, on the count of three!
サイリウムは　フリフリフリフリ
Wave your penlights! Wave, wave, wave, wave!
推して押されて　お兄さんもお姉さんも
Pushing and being pushed, brothers and sisters too!
ここまでよくできました！
You did a great job so far!
最後に一つ
One last thing...
三千回でも足りないぞ　100万回愛してる！
3,000 times isn't enough, I love you a million times!
これまでを支えてくれた
To everyone who has supported me...
皆さんに寄り添いたいなって
...I want to stay close to you
大切な仲間たちとこれからも
With my precious friends from now on too
今もずっと大好きなこの場所で
In this place that I've always loved
君もいつだって　どこだって welcome
You too, anytime and anywhere, welcome
ワクワク更新中
Excitement is updating
まだ見ぬ明日も未来も
The unseen tomorrow and the future too
共に広げましょう
Let's expand them together
泣いたって　しょげたって　大丈夫ジョーブ
Even if you cry or feel blue, it's okay, okay
笑顔で一緒に　ハイ・ファイ・ファイ！
With a smile, let's do a high-five! Five! Five!
心を歌に重ねて
Layering our hearts into the song
届けましょう
Let's deliver it
繋げましょう　いきましょう my shining world
Let's connect, let's go, my shining world
楽しい時間をみんなと過ごせて本当に幸せです
I'm truly happy to have spent this fun time with you all
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
愛してるぞ！
I love you!
Kei-ho!
Kei-yo! Yo! Yo! Yo!
よーし、新曲お披露目！行くぞ！
Alright, new song reveal! Let's go!
A-one, a-two, a-one two se-no!
A-one, a-two, a-one two, go!
あ、掛け声決めてなかった…
Oh, I didn't decide on the call-and-response...
そんなところも　カバ余余
Even that part of me is cute-yo-yo
皆落着いて　こいこい
Everyone, calm down and come, come
共に暴走して　おいおい
Let's run wild together, oi oi
赤裸歌えば　よいよい
If we sing frankly, it's good, good
この道を進むのだ
Proceed on this path
あーでもね　疲れたらゆっくりと歩みましょう
Ah, but you know, if you're tired, let's walk slowly
人生なんて気楽に構えましょう
Let's take life easy
なんてやってたら　ちゃんとしのって
While doing that, "do it properly"...
どっちどっちどっち…どっちの君は大正解
Which one, which one... whichever one you are is correct
だってこの世は　めちゃかわ余
Because this world is super cute-yo
駄目なとこも　のーかわ余
Even the bad parts are cute-yo
生まれてきてくれて　ありがとめ
Thank you for being born
皆だいだいだいだい　大好きかわ余
I love you all so, so, so much, cute-yo
ねーねーそんな　この世はかわ余
Hey hey, such a world is cute-yo
出合い別れで　君かわ余
Meetings and partings make you cute-yo
あばくさまにラブだから
Because it's an overwhelming love
あまりあるかわ余　作りましょう
Let's make lots of cute-yo
あまり振り回しすぎたる
If I swing it around too much...
もしかして呆れられちゃうかも
...you might get disappointed
取り澄みで愛してほしいな
I want you to love me forever
そんなところも　かわ余余
Even that part of me is cute-yo-yo
やめかけたら立ち止まれ
If you're about to quit, stop right there
本日もお仕事が終わりましょう
Today's work is coming to an end
でもな 自分のペースでまったりもしたいしな
But you know, I also want to relax at my own pace
どっちどっちどっち
Which one, which one, which one?
今どっちのきみも大優勝
Right now, either version of you is the grand champion
だってこの世はめちゃかわよ
Because this world is super cute
ダメな時もいい時も
In bad times and in good times
どっちもあるから愛に気づく
It's because of both that we notice love
だいたいだいたい好きな結果
Mostly, mostly, it's a result I like
ちょっとグダグダな足取りも
Even with a slightly stumbling gait
うまくいかない一日も
And even on days when nothing goes right
生きてるだけでかわなのだ
Just being alive is cute
手を顔の上に顔をさくらんぼ
Hands on the face, face like a cherry
だってこの世は鬼かわよ
Because this world is devilishly cute
完璧なところこそかわよ
Even the perfect parts are cute
出会ってくれてありがとね
Thank you for meeting me
みんなだいだいだいだい好きで
I love you all so, so, so much
ねぇねぇもっともっと世はかわよ
Hey, hey, the world is more and more cute
出会いまくれたきみとかわよ
You, whom I've met so many times, are cute
ラブってる日々はラブラブなのです
The days we're in love are lovey-dovey
騙さずにかわなよ 生きましょ
Without deception, let's live cutely
あんまり振り回しすぎたら
If I mess around too much
もしかして呆れられちゃうかも
Maybe you'll get fed up with me
懲りずにね 愛してほしいな
Without giving up on me, I want you to love me
そんな言葉も言えないし
But I can't even say those words
いつも器用にできないけど
I'm not always good at things
いつだってきみが笑えるように
But so that you can always smile
頑張るので愛してほしいな
I'll do my best, so please love me
そんなところもかわよ
Even that part of me is cute
だって世界がかわよ
Because the world is cute
今もここらへんがかわよ
Even right now, this is cute
ハイ！
Hi!
絶対御世！！Annibal
Zettai Ose!! Annibal
うおー！新曲お披露目だ！
Whoa! It's a new song reveal!
超いい曲だから最後まできいてね！
It's a super good song, so listen until the end!
行くよ！
Here we go!
約束その一
Promise number one
私以外の女とは目を合わせないこと
Don't make eye contact with any woman other than me
約束その二
Promise number two
破った場合 退所は考えないものとします
If broken, withdrawal will not be considered
本心なんて曖昧だね
True feelings are so ambiguous
独占禁止法だ
It's an Anti-Monopoly Law
束縛だって泣いちゃうくらい
Restraint to the point of crying
絶対絶対絶対絶対だめ
Is absolutely, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely forbidden
ふらふら浮つく人には
To those who are fickle and unfaithful
条件なんてあげないないない
I won't give any terms at all
やっぱり目移りです
As expected, your eyes are wandering
絶対御世 初めまして
Absolute Era, nice to meet you
休み時間 一息ももし
Recess, if even for a breath
退けないよ 乱雑だわ
I can't back down, it's messy
このまま立ってファウファあれ
Just stand there like that, fanfare
もんたいにばる
Montai-nival
私だけの特権 I want you
My exclusive privilege, I want you
絶対御世！！Annibal
Zettai Ose!! Annibal
約束その三
Promise number three
他の女に可愛いって言わないこと
Don't say "cute" to other women
約束その四
Promise number four
破ったら 針千本飲まーす 私釘付けの刑
If broken, I'll make you swallow a thousand needles, sentence you to be fixed on me
崇拝だって純愛さ
Even worship is pure love
革命前夜ファンファーレ
The fanfare on the eve of the revolution
王国だって変えちゃう未来
A future that could even change a kingdom
絶対絶対絶対絶対強制
Is absolutely, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely mandatory
よりどりみどりね 素敵よね
A wide variety, isn't it wonderful?
おぼこ様
My innocent darling
進行方向 知らないないない
Direction of progress, I don't know at all
だけどヤキモキです
But I'm feeling anxious
絶対御世 始めちゃうわ
I'm starting the Absolute Era
きみを狙ってひっきりなし
Aiming for you incessantly
一般教養 恋を先生
General education, love as the teacher
パーティー開きたくまつりごと
I want to hold a party, a festive matter
二人調べも不思議人モンチュー
Checking the two of us, a mysterious person Mon-chu
絶対御世！！Annibal
Zettai Ose!! Annibal
まずいぞ！恋一番可愛いのはだーれ？
This is bad! Who is the cutest in love?
まつりー！
Matsuri-!
ひひー！よーし！
Hee-hee! Alright!
ナイスだぞ！
Nice one!
ねえ こんなこと
Hey, things like this
言いたくないよ 本当は
I don't really want to say them
だけど本気で
But seriously
伝えておけばよかったなってさ
I wish I had told you
後悔したくないのね
I don't want to regret it
好きなのよね
Because I love you, you know?
わかって？これも愛
Understand? This is also love
絶対御世 初めまして
Absolute Era, nice to meet you
休み時間 一息ももし
Recess, if even for a breath
退けないよ 乱雑だわ
I can't back down, it's messy
このまま立ってファウファあれ
Just stand there like that, fanfare
私だけの特権 I want you
My exclusive privilege, I want you
Looking I want you
絶対推せがアニバーサリー
Always support me, it's an anniversary
そうやっててがアニバーサリー
That's how it is, it's an anniversary
旅立つ冒険、そしてインドアイの新派へ
Setting off on an adventure, to a new indoor wave
ぺこらストーリー
Pekora Story
最大級のなななななっぴー
The greatest Na-na-na-na-nappy
みんな〜！
Everyone!
おっぺこ〜！
Oppeko!
いくぺこ〜！
Here we go-peko!
最強版のタイムにビビるのが大概なマインド
It's a usual mind to fear the strongest time
（ななななっぴー）
(Na-na-na-nappy)
ワンツー、スリーで繋がった世界に愛が溢れ出す
Love overflows in a world connected by 1-2-3
（ななななっぴー）
(Na-na-na-nappy)
8ビットに感じるドキドキ
Heartbeats felt in 8-bit
罪なラブじゃダメですか？
Is sinful love not allowed?
運ゲー状態ふざけじゃねえぞ
Stop messing around with this RNG status
レベルアップして超えてやろう
Level up and overcome it
夢に見てるファンファーレの音
The sound of the fanfare from my dreams
熱情・肯定・剛毅・博打でマイロマンスを謳歌せ！
Enjoy my romance with passion, affirmation,
fortitude, and gambling!
Nappy Nappy 小さなビットででっかい相棒監視中
Nappy Nappy, monitoring a big partner
with a small bit
チョコも持っても許してね
Forgive me even if I have chocolate
いつだって愛はピコピコ
Love is always pico-pico
Jumping Jumping 跳ねるハートで捕まえに来てね
Jumping Jumping, come catch me
with a bouncing heart
ミスとなんて思わないで
Don't think of it as a mistake
グッドエンドになるまで
Until we reach a good end
最大級のなななななっぴー
The greatest Na-na-na-na-nappy
人生と賭けて無理ゲーと解く どちらもクリアが見えません
Bet on life and solve impossible games,
neither clear is in sight
このラブって状態異常を解く
Curing this status ailment called "love"
アイテムはどこで買えますか
Where can I buy the items?
経験も体力も足りない御一行
A party lacking both experience and stamina
物足りないの私のR&P
Something's missing, my R&P
まぞんな難所も超えてやるけど その前に誰かいますか？
I'll overcome masochistic hard spots,
but is anyone there first?
ちゃんと届いてるあなたのエール
Your cheers are reaching me clearly
意地・たまご・素っ気ない・絶体絶命・失敗もアクセスの助走
Will, eggs, curtness, desperation, and failure
are all run-ups to access
Nappy Nappy 小さなビットででっかい世界欲新中
Nappy Nappy, expanding my desire for a big world
with a small bit
うまくいかないプレイイング
Poor playing performance
迷走だってあなたとしたい
I want to go astray with you
私を見ててほしいの よそ見はしないでね
I want you to keep looking at me,
don't look away
縁あって愛してね
Love me if there's a connection
もっと飛べるから
Because I can fly higher
Nappy Nappy まだまだあなたとでっかい愛を更新中
Nappy Nappy, still updating a big love with you
暴走しちゃったら静止してね
Stop me if I go out of control
だって愛は非常識
Because love is irrational
まだまだ跳ねてたいから ずっとそばで見ててね
I want to keep bouncing, so stay by my side
and watch
どんな想いでもくださいな
Please give me any kind of thoughts
隙間埋めるくらいに
Enough to fill the gaps
最大級のなななななっぴー
The greatest Na-na-na-na-nappy
まだしたいのなななななっぴー
Still want more Na-na-na-na-nappy
OK OK 僕か君の神様になってあげる
OK OK, I'll become your god
悩める現代の皆様 けたたましい時代の真ん中
To all troubled modern people,
in the middle of a noisy era
自分のことさえ愛せない そんなことありませんか？
Can't even love yourself, isn't that how it is?
誰かに認めてもらいたいな 何もうまくいかずやだやだ
Wanting someone to acknowledge you,
nothing goes well, no no
神頼み不本意なのに どこにいったら会えるの神様
Praying against your will,
where can I go to meet God?
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
うんうん
Yeah, yeah
そっか大変だね
I see, that's tough
でもね
But you know
大丈夫！僕が味方でいるからさ
It's okay! Because I'm on your side
生きてるだけで満点！
Just for being alive, you get full marks!
自信持ちなよ全然！
Have some confidence, totally!
全然！
Totally!
信じていいよ当然！
You can believe it, of course!
当然！
Of course!
君はとっても素敵だよ！
You are very wonderful!
ありとあらゆるこの世のすべてが
Everything and anything in this world
肯定！肯定！
Affirmation! Affirmation!
肯定！
Affirmation!
全知全能 全肯定！
Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation!
全知全能 全肯定
Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation
それって結構神じゃない？
Isn't that pretty god-like?
いいじゃんいいじゃんすごいじゃん
It's good, it's good, it's amazing
いいじゃんいいじゃんえらいじゃん
It's good, it's good, you're great
そうですそうですもっと自由に 生きていいんだよ全肯定
That's right, that's right, you can live more freely,
total affirmation
いいじゃんいいじゃんすごいじゃん
It's good, it's good, it's amazing
いいじゃんいいじゃんえらいじゃん
It's good, it's good, you're great
OK OK 君は最高 何度だって伝えてあげる
OK OK, you're the best, I'll tell you
as many times as it takes
承認欲求マウント社会 毎日頑張ってる君が優勝
In a social climber society, you're the winner
for doing your best every day
...否定
...negation.
誰もがみんな求め続ける 自分だけにある特別感
A sense of specialness that belongs only to oneself, which everyone keeps seeking.
数値化されちゃう世知辛い時代
Hard times where everything gets quantified.
いいね フォロワー 高評価
Likes, followers, and high ratings.
そんなの全然必要ないよ
Those are not necessary at all.
僕の言葉に全てゆだねて
Entrust everything to my words.
あーね！いいじゃん！うんうん！えらい！
I see! That's good! Yeah, yeah! You're great!
おー！完璧！今日の疲れ！
Oh! Perfect! Today's fatigue!
ずっと！けっこう！肯定！肯定！
Always! Quite good! Affirmation! Affirmation!
さすが！自信もって！
As expected! Have confidence!
すばらしせかい ちそがいおるよ
Wonderful world, I'm here by your side.
大好き 超好き つまり好き
I love you, love you so much, in other words, I love you.
できるよ 当然 なんとかなるよ
You can do it, naturally, it'll work out.
にっこり ぬくぬく ねこかわいがり
Smiling, warmly, doting on you like a cat.
神様も 仏様も 何もかも 信じられなくても
Even if you can't believe in God, Buddha, or anything else.
ねこ様を 信じましょう 甘えましょう 与えましょう 安心
Let's believe in the Cat God, let's depend on her, let's give, peace of mind.
晴れの日も 雨の日も 支えましょう 君の心を
On sunny days or rainy days, I'll support your heart.
病める時 泣ける時 ここに来たなら もう大丈夫
When you're sick or when you cry, if you come here, you'll be fine.
はい！はい！よしよし！
Yes! Yes! There, there!
うんうん！心配しないで
Yeah, yeah! Don't worry.
ほらね 大丈夫
See? It's okay.
君もレッツ おにぎりゃー！
You too, let's Onigirya!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん
It's good, it's good, it's amazing.
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん
It's good, it's good, you're great.
そうです そうです もっと僕の そばにおいでよ 全肯定
That's right, that's right, come closer to me, total affirmation.
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん
It's good, it's good, it's amazing.
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん
It's good, it's good, you're great.
オッケー オッケー 僕が君の ねこ様になってあげる
Okay, okay, I'll become your Cat God.
のんびりいこうよ ばっちり愉快
Let's take it easy, perfectly pleasant.
ファンタスティック へっちゃらポジティブ
Fantastic, unbothered and positive.
まあまあ みんな 無理しないでね
Now, now, everyone, don't overdo it.
めっちゃ心配だよ
I'm really worried about you.
おかゆが やっぱり 1番 勇気の よっしゃいくぞ！
Okayu is indeed the best, here we go with courage!
肯定！肯定！肯定！肯定！
Affirmation! Affirmation! Affirmation! Affirmation!
前進 全能 全肯定！
Progress, omnipotence, total affirmation!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん
It's good, it's good, it's amazing.
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん
It's good, it's good, you're great.
オッケー オッケー 新世界の 神様になってあげる
Okay, okay, I'll become the God of the new world.
楽にいこうよ
Let's take it easy.
笑ってこ！
Let's smile!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
(歓声)
(Cheers)
ということで皆さん、hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade DAY2始まりましたー！
And so, everyone, hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade DAY2 has begun!
イエーイ！
Yay!
じゃあ、自己紹介していきましょうかね。
Well then, shall we introduce ourselves?
お願いします。
Please do.
皆さーん！
Everyone!
コンコンきーつね！ コンコンきーつね！ And hi friends!
Kon kon kitsune! Kon kon kitsune! And hi friends!
ホロライブ1期生兼ゲーマーズ、白上フブキでーす！
Hololive 1st Gen and Gamers member, Shirakami Fubuki here!
そして！
And next!
コンぺこー！
Kon-peko!
コンぺこ コンぺこ コンぺこー！ ホロライブ3期生の兎田ぺこらぺこー！
Kon-peko, kon-peko, kon-peko! Hololive 3rd Gen's Usada Pekora-peko!
イエーイ！
Yay!
こんぺこ、あー、忘れてたぺこ。忘れてたぺこ...
Kon-peko, ah, I forgot-peko. I forgot...
緊張してたぺこな。忘れてたぺこの緊張が...
I was so nervous-peko. I forgot because of my nervousness...
今ね、さっきね、ソロで歌いましたけども...
I just finished my solo performance just now, but...
ぺこちゃん、ソロで歌ってたもんね。
Pekora-chan, you were singing solo, weren't you?
ねー、もうめちゃめちゃ緊張したぺこ。緊張したぺこなのよ。
Yeah, I was super nervous-peko. I was really nervous.
でも皆さん盛り上がってましたよ！
But everyone was getting really excited!
盛り上がってましたぺこかー！？
Were they excited-peko!?
いいねー。配信勢のみんなも、あ、すごい、皆さん書いてくれてる。ありがとう。
That's great. Everyone in the stream too, oh wow, everyone is typing. Thank you.
ねー、配信勢もコメント、アーモンドになってる！
Yeah, even the stream comments are turning into almonds!
あー、ありがとうぺこな。ありがとう。
Ah, thank you-peko. Thank you.
いや、そうだぺこちゃん。
No, that's right, Pekora-chan.
ん？
Hmm?
やっぱさ、ライブと言ったらさ、コール&レスポンスなんだけども。
After all, when you think of a live concert, it's about call and response.
吹雪ちゃん。
Fubuki-chan.
やりたかったぺこらも！
I wanted to do it too-peko!
超やりたかったぺこ！
I super wanted to do it-peko!
あれをやってほしいの。
I want you to do that thing.
あ、あれ？
Ah, that?
ドドンドドンドドン。
Do-don-do-don-do-don.
あれを？ ちょっとやりたくて。
That? I kind of wanted to do it.
なるほど、なるほど。
I see, I see.
あの、ぺこらの挨拶のあれですね。
That's the thing from Pekora's greeting, right?
そう、あれ、あれ。お、ちょっと白上もオマージュしてやりたいんですけども、
Yes, that one, that one. Oh, I also want to do a Shirakami homage to it,
まずはやっぱりぺこちゃんの、ね。皆さんもね、言いたいですもんね。
but first, it's Pekora-chan's turn. Everyone wants to say it too, right?
まぁ、皆さん分かってますぺこですよね。あれですよね、
Well, everyone knows it-peko, right? It's that thing where,
ぺこらが言ったらみんなが「ぺこちゃーん」って。
when Pekora says it, everyone says "Pekora-chan!"
そう、「ぺこちゃーん」って、「ぺこちゃーん」ですよ。
Yes, "Pekora-chan!" like that, "Pekora-chan!"
わかりました。いきますよ。
Got it. Here I go.
はい。
Okay.
じゃあ、いきますよ！
Then, here I go!
ドドンドドンドドン！ 全VTuber一、超絶可愛いのは誰だー！？
Do-don-do-don-do-don! Who is the most super-duper cute VTuber in the world!?
ドドンドドンドドン！
Do-don-do-don-do-don!
ぺこちゃーん！
Pekora-chan!
あー！素晴らしい！
Ah! Wonderful!
じゃあ、ちょっと白上もやらせていただきます。
Now, let Shirakami have a turn too.
お、フブちゃんバージョンがあるみたいぺこなんで、お願いします。
Oh, it looks like there's a Fubu-chan version-peko, so please go ahead.
フブちゃんですからね. いきますよ。
Since it's Fubu-chan. Here I go.
コンコンコンコンコン！
Kon kon kon kon kon!
全VTuber一、可愛いキツネは誰だー！？
Who is the cutest fox VTuber in the world!?
こんこんこんこん！ヘイ、ビートちゃん！
Kon kon kon kon! Hey, Beat-chan!
これからあれ、使っていいってことですからね、すないぺ。
From now on, we can use that, you know? Snai-pe!
え、本当に？こんこんこんこんいいんぺこ？
Wait, really? Is "Kon kon kon kon" okay, peko?
めちゃめちゃいいと思うぺこよ。
I think it's perfectly fine, peko.
やったー！こんこんこんこん！イエーイ！
Yay! Kon kon kon kon! Yay!
マジで？はい。
For real? Yes.
お、何で？フブキちゃん。
Oh, what's up, Fubuki-chan?
ぺこらもさ、やりたいのがあの、フブキちゃんのさ…
Pekora also wants to do that thing of Fubuki-chan's...
…何百回愛してるみたいな。
...like the "I love you hundreds of times" thing.
あー、あれをぺこらもやりたいのぺこ、フブキちゃん。
Ah, Pekora also wants to do that, Fubuki-chan.
やりたい？やりたい？やりたい？
You want to? You want to? You want to?
やりたい、やりたい、やりたいぺこ！
I want to, I want to, I want to, peko!
じゃあ白上がお手本見せますね。
Then Shirakami will show you how it's done.
じゃあ白上が「白上のこと何万回好き？」って言ったら
So when Shirakami asks, "How many million times
do you like Shirakami?"
皆さん答えるの分かりますよね？
You all know how to answer, right?
分かるぺこ。
We know, peko!
言ってください、出来ますよ。
Go ahead, we can do it.
白上のこと何万回好き？
How many million times do you like Shirakami?
100万回愛してるよ！
We love you a million times!
あーー！やったーー！良かったー、良かった。
Ahhh! Yay! Good, that was great.
「好き」って言ったのにね、ちゃんと「愛してる」って返してくれるんですよ。
Even though I said "like," they properly
responded with "love."
じゃあぺこらもそれ答えてくれるのかな？
Then, will they answer the same for Pekora?
あ、ちょっと答えるしかないな。準備！
Ah, we have no choice but to answer. Ready!
おし！準備よし！
Alright! Ready!
準備よしとしてくれてる。
They're getting ready.
フブキちゃんお願いします。
Fubuki-chan, if you please.
はい。
Yes.
じゃあみんなも準備いいぺこだね？
Then is everyone ready, peko?
ぺこらのこと何万回好き？
How many million times do you like Pekora?
100万回愛してるよ！
We love you a million times!
いよっしゃー！ありがとう！イエーイ！
Alright! Thank you! Yay!
いや、いいねやっぱね、声が出せるってね。
Man, it's great after all, being able to shout.
本当に、気持ちいい！最高！
Really, it feels so good! The best!
最高、最高ですよ。ありがとうございます。
It's the best, the best. Thank you very much.
ありがとうみんな！
Thank you, everyone!
さてさて、まず1曲ソロでね、終わりましたけども。
Well then, our first solo songs have ended.
改めて歌ってみてどうでした？
How did it feel singing them just now?
いやぺこらはもう、満身創痍というか。
Well, Pekora is just completely exhausted.
いや本当に。なんか、でもみんなが目の前にいてね…
No, really. Like, seeing everyone right in front of me...
こうやって「ハイ！ハイ！」とかやってくれたりしながらもう…
...while they were doing the "Hai! Hai!" calls...
感動だし緊張もあったぺこだけど。
I was moved, and also nervous, peko.
なんかもう、楽しい、本当に楽しい！みんなありがとうね今日本当に。
But it's just so fun, really fun! Thank you
all so much for today.
まだまだこれからだけどね！
There's still more to come, though!
そうだね、まだまだこれからだけどね！
Right, there's still plenty more to come!
白上もみんなのコールちゃんと聞こえてたぞ！ありがとう！
Shirakami could clearly hear everyone's calls! Thank you!
フブキちゃん、フブキちゃんは？
Fubuki-chan, how about you, Fubuki-chan?
え、もう本当に楽しかった。トップバッターだったんだけど交代…
Oh, it was really fun. I was the top batter,
but since the switch...
そうだったよね！
That's right!
そう！なんかね、スーパー白上タイムとかいって。
Yeah! Like, having that "Super Shirakami Time."
ちょっとね、みんな「はにゃあ」ってなってたかもしれないんですけど。
I was a bit worried everyone might have been
confused, though.
いや、白上タイムぺこだったよ！
No, it was a total Shirakami Time, peko!
あー、本当にありがとう！
Ah, thank you so much!
さてさて、今回のハッシュタグなんですけど皆さん分かってますよね？
Well then, you all know the hashtag
for this time, right?
分かってるぺこでしょ！
They definitely know, peko!
ハッシュタグ、#ひろがるホロライブDAY2 です！
The hashtag is #HirogaruHololiveDAY2!
こちらいっぱい呟いてください！お願いします！
Please tweet using it a lot! We're counting on you!
ぜひぜひ、スクショも！
And screenshots too, please!
あ、そうだぺこ、うさぺこのね、スクショもぜひぜひ！
Oh, right peko, take lots of screenshots
of Usapeko too!
お願いします！お願いします！
Please do! Please do!
そしてなんと悲しいお知らせです。
And now, we have some sad news.
え？
Huh?
YouTubeでご覧の皆様はここまでとなります。
This is the end for those watching on YouTube.
えーーー！
Ehhhh!
まだまだね、一緒にみんなで盛り上がっていきたいので…
We still want to keep the excitement going
together with everyone...
ぜひ概要欄から配信サイトへ！
So please head to the streaming site
via the description!
よろぺこ！チケットもよろぺこ！
Please do, peko! Get your tickets too, peko!
ということでまだまだね、これから盛り上がっていきますので。
And so, things are only going to get
more exciting from here.
締めの言葉いきますか？
Shall we do the closing words?
いきましょう！
Let's do it!
せーの！ひろがる…ホロライブ！
One, two! Hirogaru... Hololive!
無料パートは終了いたしました！
The free viewing part has ended!
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching!
無料パートは終了いたしました！
The free portion has ended!
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching!